No wonder the name sounded familiar.
I was Je Moon-jae too.
I said I'm Je Moon-jae!
MOUSETRAP
Ms. Han, let me explain it in person.
You're the only person I can rely on now.
I'll explain everything in person.
Please just hear me out.
Say something already!
Why won't you say anything?
Ms. Han.
See?
I told you he'd call again.
Thank you for the drink.
I'm sorry for showing up unannounced.
Still, we should do this again sometime.
You have a knife.
Just kill me already, you bastard!
Come on, pick up.
You can't park here.
It's by the sea. It's dangerous.
Okay, I'll move right away.
Have you been drinking?
No.
Step out for a moment.
-Sorry?
-Sir.
Wanted vehicle. Urgent.
Is this your vehicle?
Please step out.
I don't understand what's going on.
Where the hell is Sun-yong anyway?
What do you mean your name's Moon-jae?
I used to be Je Moon-jae too.
You know I'm an orphan.
The bastard who dragged me into this
even had my adoption records.
Hey, man.
How could you forget your childhood name?
You've been after Je Moon-jae
for a while now.
Come on.
Do you still fucking
remember everything clearly
from when you were five?
I've got a lot of names.
I was adopted and returned three times.
I think my first name was Sang-gyu,
Sang-gu, hogu, or something.
Fucking hell.
What was the next one? Hyeon-cheol?
The next one's Park Sun-yong.
But my name was Je Moon-jae
when I was five.
Damn.
No wonder it sounded fucking familiar.
I said get out of the car.
-That's not it.
-I said step out for a moment.
Don't move! Damn it.
Get out of the car, you bastard!
Get out!
But…
who are you?
Requesting backup.
Don't move, you bastard.
He said we should rest before we return.
Get some sleep.
Hey, who is it?
Where is the bastard?
He's fine.
That's enough. Bring him out.
Yes, sir.
Hey.
Get in here.
Hey, you bastard. Get in here.
Where's Noja?
I don't know.
Three of our guys died,
you fucking piece of shit!
One of them was expecting a second child,
so he even bought drinks.
You son of a bitch.
Why did our guys have to die
over trash like you?
Tell me where he is.
Noja.
Tell me!
You fucking bastard.
HOW DID IT GO?
PARK SEUNG-GYU
Yeah, I was just about to call you.
I got Noja, that bastard,
and found that old man.
DEOKAM NURSING HOME
Hello.
Apparently, a bunch of cops
already came by and left.
But he has dementia.
Doesn't know his own name.
Remembers nothing.
So there's nothing to be scared of.
That old man, he can't prove anything.
So what do we do now?
How do I get my money?
Fuck. You're right.
I didn't even think about that.
Okay.
Got it. Okay.
Why the fuck is he asking me
to send this shit?
Hey, call the guy at the nursing home.
We've missed something.
Please call that detective.
Then I'll explain everything.
Where are you going?
The nursing home.
WRITER JE MOON-JAE
-Yep.
-Hello, detective. It's Je Moon-jae.
Oh, I know.
But what's this about?
I heard you found my uncle.
Yep.
Then that makes things simpler.
One simple DNA test
will tell you who the real one is.
I just have a feeling you suspect me.
I was thinking the same thing.
I'm actually on my way
to the nursing home.
Are you sure
you're okay with the DNA test?
Of course. Where's my uncle?
I'll head over right now.
I guess you can do that.
First, I'll collect your uncle's hair
and a buccal swab, and…
What the hell?
For fuck's sake.
The patient inhaled a lot of smoke.
For fuck's sake, seriously!
Excuse me!
Excuse me. That old man. The elderly man.
He should be nearby. Everyone's out.
-Really?
-It's so hectic.
He should be over there.
He was in the same room as them.
-There?
-Yes.
Okay.
Why are you trembling?
You seemed fine burying your friend there.
What
did I do wrong?
Huh?
If I did something wrong,
I'm sorry.
Really.
I'm really sorry!
Fuck.
Did you even know that I liked you?
I was obsessed with you.
I did everything you told me to do
to fucking impress you.
I did all your dirty work,
and you don't even fucking know who I am.
To someone as mighty as you,
I must've been fucking nobody.
And the mighty man got scammed
and lost fucking everything.
Was that money yours?
Did you make it?
I made it, you son of a bitch.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry!
You didn't even know I gave you work
and helped you
when you were broke, did you?
Fuck, you did a hell of a lot of bad shit.
Ten times more than me.
Ten times? Definitely more. Fuck.
Acting all high and mighty,
burying people there.
Did it make you feel like a god?
No.
Not at all.
You're not the only one who's gonna die.
So don't be too upset.
I'll bury every fucking bastard
who knows about my past
and leave this country.
Everyone. Even that asshole.
Gotta start a new game.
What if I beg for forgiveness?
Will you spare me?
Go ahead, then.
I'm sorry.
I was wrong.
Please spare me.
Never again!
You'll never see me again!
Just let me live!
Please.
-Sir.
-Good night, sir!
Treat yourself to something nice.
Thank you, sir!
Do you remember?
That time you gave me money.
I was so fucking scared
'cause I thought I was gonna die.
There was a time I wanted to be like you.
But I guess I can't anymore.
I'm sorry, but it's too late.
No!
Please!
Spare me!
No!
No! Just spare my life!
Here's your money back.
Bury him.
Aren't you gonna sleep?
I'm thinking.
About what?
The dog I had when I was a kid.
We kept it tied up in the yard
to guard the house.
It guarded the house its whole life
until it died of old age.
But until it died,
it never saw the world beyond that leash.
The length of that leash
was its whole world.
It must've been dying to get out of there.
I don't remember the dog's name,
but as for the leash…
I even remember the color of that leash.
Maybe it's not that I remember the dog,
but that I remember the leash.
Now that I think of it,
in a way,
that leash was the mark of the dog.
Come to think of it, I'm the same too.
Hey, here. Do you see it?
The leash.
There's nothing there.
Everyone has memories they want to erase.
But this leash
is woven from the memories
you want to erase.
Right when you think it's gone,
it grabs you by the throat.
In the end,
people die by that leash.
Hey, didn't you say
your memories were fading?
Don't forget about that leash, you punk,
or you'll…
never be able to prove who you are.
Je Moon-jae.
It's not even a good name.
Why the hell are you fighting over it?
The fake one kills someone,
frames the other,
and pretends to be the real one?
Fuck, who's the real one?
And who's the fake?
Huh?
You wanted to see me.
Please help me.
I've got
no one but you.
What about Noja?
I don't know.
We lost touch.
There he is.
This…
They sent this to you.
He died?
You won't even find the body.
That's the cleanest way.
You found your uncle.
Why did you just leave?
You bastard. Damn it.
He remembered nothing.
There was no point.
DNA.
Hey. What's up with your face?
I'm helping you right now.
You should be happy
if you're the real one.
Can it…
Can it be this easy?
After you came by and left…
your uncle disappeared.
Someone burned down the nursing home
and took it all, even his toothbrush.
In case he left DNA behind.
I knew it.
It can't be this easy.
That's how it's always been so far.
That bastard knows everything about me.
He knows me better than I do.
I see.
So you don't know anything about this?
I was caught
right after I left the nursing home.
I couldn't have moved him.
Maybe you've got some bastard helping you.
I did.
They're tracking his movements on CCTV.
Your uncle.
You don't even have an alibi.
So if we can't find him,
you're the fake one.
That's why I asked to see you.
I'll tell you everything
that's happened so far.
Who he is,
what happened…
and how it ended up like this.
Hey, guys. Listen up.
I first met him
at an intercollegiate literature club.
We got a new member today.
What? Is he handsome?
Introduce yourself.
Hello, I'm the new club member,
Seo Yu-min.
It's very nice to meet you all.
Welcome.
His first impression wasn't good.
How should I put it?
He had a ravenous look in his eyes,
like he hadn't eaten in days.
The kind of look that makes you think
he'd devour anything.
THE RAT THAT ATE FINGERNAILS
Moon-jae, did you write this?
Why? You think it's good?
It's amazing.
I'm jealous.
I wish I could write like you.
Man.
But I'm too lazy.
I still have this much to write,
but I'm getting nowhere.
Actually, there's someone who inspires me.
Who is it?
You're gonna wear it out.
The two of us grew close quickly.
This is how people end up alcoholics…
It was because of Min-yeong.
Bathroom.
We both…
Get me one more.
…liked Min-yeong.
She can really hold her liquor.
What is it?
Moon-jae.
What's the deal with you two?
What do you mean?
We just go to the same school.
You're sure, right?
Whether I'm sure or not,
talking about this is meaningless.
Why is it meaningless?
Min-yeong is way out of our league.
Her standards are super high.
We're not even close.
She's definitely out of your league.
But not mine.
That summer,
the three of us went on a trip together.
But something happened there.
Min-yeong.
I've got something to tell you.
Let's talk.
You're drunk. Talk tomorrow.
Let go! I just wanna talk to her.
You said you two weren't a thing.
We're dating.
We kept it a secret at the club
because he said he'd feel uncomfortable.
Since when?
Before you asked me.
You shouldn't toy with people.
Don't you fucking think so?
You are just
jealous of me.
You're dying of jealousy
because you want to be me.
Aren't you?
Shut up, you son of a bitch!
That was the last time I ever saw him.
I hadn't seen him since that day.
Until he came back with my face.
You're saying he did all this
just for that?
I don't understand either.
Is this really worth all this?
He went ballistic,
like someone took what was his.
Does it make any sense that he changed
his face to yours and killed that girl
after all this time?
There must be more to it, you bastard.
There is.
Something I didn't know about.
I heard about this later,
but that bastard
wasn't even a university student.
He was pretending to be one
from the start.
Creepy, isn't it?
What happened between you and that girl?
Well,
it just fizzled out.
I heard she met someone later
and lived with him.
We shouldn't have gone on that trip.
That trip's what caused all this mess.
Tell me about your parents.
Prove that you're the real one.
Something the fake one wouldn't know.
My mom
had some mental issues.
I don't know why,
but ever since I was born,
our home was never like other families'.
My father said I took after my mom.
Maybe that's why I inherited
her illness too.
After that,
I could feel myself losing my mind.
I couldn't live without my meds.
I'm still like that now.
Maybe it's the meds,
but my old memories are fading.
Once I completely forget who I am,
he will become the real one, right?
The vanity in the bedroom.
What did it look like?
It was just…
a regular vanity.
Black.
A black one.
With no patterns.
Not even shiny. Just black.
A square-shaped one.
A rectangle.
How did you know?
We had one like that at home too.
Now I fucking get it.
My role was to put you in jail.
For one, you don't have much time.
And no alibi either.
Everything you have
is evidence against you.
If you get indicted like this,
you're done.
If you have anything more to add,
tell me now.
Anything that proves you're the real one.
All of it.
Yes, that property damage case.
The one with the smashed car.
CONSTRUCTION EQUIPMENT PARTS DEALER
Sir, have a good one.
-So you didn't see anything?
-No, I didn't.
Thank you.
I mean, why are we here looking for CCTVs?
How did this become our case?
The one who knows
is at the police station.
I mean, why's he at another station?
Major Crimes called him.
Seriously.
Hello?
What? Why?
What? Well…
Find anything?
Nothing, of course.
I mean, you have to tell me why…
Who is it? Is it Sun-yong?
-Let me talk to that bastard.
-He hung up.
-What?
-Wait, so…
What did the captain say?
He said to leave Chang-u here.
-He wants the rest of us at the station.
-Me?
Why?
He said he'll tell us when we're there.
That damn bastard.
INTERROGATION ROOM 1
Let's take a break.
We should have him change clothes too.
Let's call for backup.
We have to find Noja's body
or something to close this case.
Seung-gyu and his men are probably nearby.
If we go back to Seoul now,
we won't get anything out of this.
I mean, but why did he ask for you? Huh?
He didn't even say anything useful.
I guess I make people comfortable.
Unlike detectives who beat people.
Maybe that wasn't funny.
You know how our job is.
You get close chasing people around.
He started falling apart
after finding out Noja was dead.
He's slowly starting to talk,
so I'll try to dig deeper.
Go grab lunch.
Just order us two bowls of gukbap.
Let's just go eat.
Let's go.
All right, enjoy your lunch!
Where's my uncle?
Come with me.
INTERROGATION ROOM 2
Where's my uncle?
You didn't even remember him.
Desperate to see him now?
I guess people really are drawn
to the same blood.
The CSI team's coming to take your DNA.
So sit down and wait a bit.
Should I get you something to drink?
Then wait here for a moment.
"Just smuggle him out for now"?
What's going on here?
Sir, the whole team's necks
are on the line.
You might even lose your pension.
To hell with it!
Let's just do it.
-Right on.
-Yeah.
Hey, you heard that, right?
We're all risking our necks for this.
-Hurry up, punk.
-Got it? Just follow us quietly.
HAN CHANG-U:
FOUND THE SUSPECT VEHICLE.
TRACED ITS MOVEMENTS.
WHERE IS EVERYONE ANYWAY?
Sir!
Sir, over here.
Here.
Go in. Here.
Yes, here.
You haven't eaten, right?
Well, I felt bad eating by myself.
Let's eat together, all right?
Sir, how much is it?
Wait. I'm not sure I have any coins.
You wanted coffee, right?
Yes.
Oh man.
Hey, you bastard.
He traced the uncle's movements.
We have to find him first.
Hurry up and go.
Hey, you bastard.
Oh, and
I found out
who the woman in the river was.
I'll join you
after checking one more thing.
Go as fast as you can.
Check what?
The evidence that the bastard
is the real one.
What did he say?
No fucking idea.
He said this one's the real one.
It wasn't bad, right?
I actually liked the other place better.
I'm so tired.
You should see this, sir.
What the hell?
Why did he change the interrogation room?
He said he lost him.
He lost an old man
who was barely even alive?
Goddamn it. Fucking bastards.
Which mountain is that?
What do we do?
What do you think? Turn the car around.
You fucking dumbasses!
Fuck.
PARK SEUNG-GYU
Hey, it's me.
He said he lost him.
I'll take care of it. Don't worry.
Fucking idiots.
Hey! That bastard's looking at a phone!
Where did he get it? Hey!
Who are you?
Me?
I'm Je Moon-jae.
Je Moon-jae, the complainant and victim!
Isn't that it?
Yeah, that's it. 1917.
Man, how are we supposed to find him here?
Even the whole Mobile Police Unit
would take a month.
We can't even use drones.
The forest's too dense.
If he went up some remote mountain,
he'd have left traces unless he's a ghost.
Quit whining and follow me, punk.
Time is precious.
-Get your gear.
-Okay.
What about him?
Hey, cuff him to the steering wheel.
Oh, I'll come with you and help.
My uncle is the only evidence.
I'm with the police.
I'd like to check some school records.
He's not here.
STUDENT RECORD
SO MIN-YEONG
What are you talking about? No way.
We never had a student by that name.
Could it have been another school?
No. It's definitely this school.
Please check again.
The student records from the '70s on
have all been computerized.
He wouldn't be from the '60s, right?
Even students who dropped out are in here.
If he's not here, he never attended.
Seo Yu-min.
Can you try searching Seo Yu-min?
Seo Yu-min?
Oh, that name's here.
Korean Language and Literature.
He and the girl from that record
were in the same major.
I heard about this later,
but that bastard
wasn't even a university student.
He was pretending to be one
from the start.
Creepy, isn't it?
It was just a regular vanity. Damn it.
I said it first.
Before I even asked him
what it looked like.
Fuck.
Yes, sir.
I can't hear you. Say that again.
We're following the trail.
What? Who?
Yeah, he came with us.
He said he wanted to help.
Huh?
Where did he go?
Sir!
Yeah? What is it?
What is it?
What?
Here…
Where's Je Moon-jae?
Goddamn it.
-Where is he?
-He's gone.
-What?
-This is bullshit. Seriously.
They won't find my uncle.
He was buried somewhere on this mountain,
gone forever, just like Noja.
I have to catch the Rat.
That's the only way.
How am I supposed to prove I'm human?
No.
Even if I were the Rat,
how could I ever admit it?
Subtitle translation by: Sung In Jang